John Kirianki Pius

P.O Box 78392, code 00507 | Cell: +254722981241 | e-mail: john.k.pius@gsk.com

Personal Summary

Strong managerial background with senior level local / international experience and interdepartmental exposure. Good strategic appreciation and vision, able to build and implement sophisticated plans with a proven track record explicitly supporting business needs. Self driven and self reliant, sets aims and targets and leads by example, collaborative approach with good interpersonal skills to engage, motivate and encourage others through change.

Highly focused with a consistent track record of successfully delivering full lifecycle implementations to tight time scales and within budget. Currently looking at growth and expansion initiatives within product development at GlaxoSmithKline site, aimed at building into the site sustainability.

Education

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN PHARMACEUTICAL CHEMISTRY| INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, SLIGO 2016 - 2018

MASTERS OF SCIENCE IN PROJECT MANAGEMENT | SEPT 2011 - NOV-2013 | JOMO KENYATTA UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE AND TECHNOLOGY (JKUAT)

- · Mastery in theoretical and practical discipline of Project management.
- · Published Academic Journal (International Journal of Academic Research in Business and Social Sciences: September 2013, Vol. 3, No. 9 ISSN: 2222-6990)

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | 1993 - 1997 | UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI

- · Major: Chemistry
- · Related coursework: Physical Chemistry, Organic Chemistry, Inorganic Chemistry, Molecular Chemistry and Industrial Chemistry

Skills & Abilities

MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS

· Knowledge and application of the ISO 9001:2008, ISO 22000, ISO 14001/OHSAS 18001 Standards and Global Quality management System. Currently Member of the KEBS Standards Review Committee.

PROJECTS DISCIPLINE:

- · High discipline in project leadership, drive and deliver projects success through from design, through execution to delivery of final objectives.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ High competency in product projects, Transfer activities and innovation.

PEOPLE SKILLS:

Have worked profitably with a wide range of people within the site and across Global GSK network.

Project Lead for product transfer in West Africa (Nigeria and Ghana)

COMMUNICATION

· Extensive experience of consultation with various departments, employing negotiation skills.

LEADERSHIP

• Demonstration of high level of integrity, openness and honesty in drive for continuous improvement, people focused through involvement and simplification of the ways of working. Trained Auditor (Level 1 and Level 2), problem solving skills as well.

KEY TRAININGS:

- · Trained on the following business performance principles:
 - · Leading and Managing Lean sigma (Nigeria)
 - · Living Safety facilitation by Keil charter of Psychologist, UK (Egypt).
 - · Lead Market for Nutritionals Product (UK)
 - · Bullet Proof Manager, by Raiser Group (Kenya)
 - · Product Development and Product Transfers (Egypt)
 - · Operation Excellence (Kenya)
 - · Process Improvement through Statistical Approach (UK)
 - · Environmental Management Principles (Kenya)
 - · Leading High Performance Teams (Kenya)
 - · Lean Sigma and defect management (Kenya)
 - · Customer Care (Kenya)
 - · My PSR (Egypt by Network Change Lead)
 - · FPAC (Egypt by Network Change Lead)

Experience

HEAD, TECHNICAL DEPARTMENT | GLAXOSMITHKLINE | OCT 2015 - TO DATE

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:

- · Product introduction and product development projects, and sharing expertise across the MEA & ISC region
- · Pro-actively identify process defects/ waste and ensure they are adequately managed.
- · Site Product Life cycle Management (PLM) lead driving the process optimization as well as process understanding, through knowledge management.
- · Leading the product and process assurance activities to deliver confidence in the site production and support systems, to deliver the required business growth.
- · Working alongside with the other site functions to deliver site growth plans and strategic objectives and to meet service, quality, safety and financial standards

· Achievements:

- · Achieved all key milestones for the site PLM requirements.
- · People development: developed team capability the direct personnel on business projects.
- · Business continuity Planning continues to lead the site teams on emergency response preparedness and business continuity planning.
- · Instrumental in developing the technical regional strategy 2016 (Cape Town) & 2017 (NAIROBI)
- \cdot Continues to lead the site Manufacturing strategy and Strategic Workforce Planning.

HEAD, NEW PRODUCT INTRODUCTION | GLAXOSMITHKLINE | OCT 2011 - TO OCT 2015

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:

- · Managing new product introduction activities, and commercial interface through the gate process
- · Leading Joint Planning Sessions (JPS) through integrated team approach.
- · Providing site representation to the Global product change groups.
- · Working with commercial leadership to explore opportunities for growth in the existing and new ventures.
- · Providing cost models to guide entire business in the investment decision.
- · Leading site impact assessment programme, capability and technology assessment and product fit
- Product & Process Development including generation, maintenance & review of product structures & Bills of Materials

· Achievements:

- · Successful execution of product introduction activities as follows:
- · 2011 Approval of Business case for 4 pharma product SKUs
- 2012 2015: Execution of product transfers from Cairo and Johannesburg to site. Achieved 12 products introductions to site.
- · Supporting Ghana in product projects
- · Local Packaging of Chlorhexidine Gel
- · Working with GSK global strategy team on Africa 2020 Initiative, in future factory design.

PRODUCTION LEAD, LIQUIDS VALUE STREAM | GLAXOSMITHKLINE | APR 2010 - OCT 2011

· Key Responsibilities:

- · Management, control and review of the value stream of CAPEX and OPEX
- · Design principle in Value stream line improvements.
- · Project Leader for the site value stream system improvement.
- $\cdot\,$ Improve productivity and overall equipment effectiveness.
- · Budgeting and resource alignments to deliver value.
- · Operational and Behavioral safety facilitation
- · Delivery of value and providing required Leadership in both human resources and product supply.
- $\cdot\,$ Environmental Health and Safety facilitator for the site value stream operations.
- Providing leadership to the sectional quality council, value stream supply board meetings and Employee safety Framework

· Achievements:

- · Performance management system on production floor
- · New Tetra Line
- $\cdot\,$ New Sugar Loading system in Nutritionals Line.
- · Talent identification and value stream alignment.

PRODUCT AND PROCESS DEVELOPMENT TECHNOLOGIST | GLAXOSMITHKLINE | APR 2003 - APR 2010

· Key Responsibilities:

- · Validation of the production equipment and interfaces.
- · Identification and management of the manufacturing process critical control points.
- · Product and Process improvement in toothpaste, pharmaceutical liquids, energy drinks and health drinks
- · Defect management for product and process.
- · Formulation development and product structure management.
- · Co-ordination and implementation of new product trials.
- · Pro-active Risk management.
- · Project Leadership and line upgrade initiatives.
- · Data analysis and reporting.
- · Training in GMP and System usage during handover to production.
- · Review of Standards for Toothpaste, health drinks and energy drinks.
- · Generation of Batch records and Standard Operating procedures.
- · Carrying out Gap analysis of the Validation Systems

· Achievements:

- Successful implementation of process improvement systems (Pasteurizer system, online carbonation and online process monitoring systems in nutritional line.)
- · Process Matrixing to ensure multiple products can be processed in same line.
- · Shelf life extension for Nutritionals Products through statistical methods.
- · Success on all validation related audits.

PROCESS CHEMIST | GLAXOSMITHKLINE | NOV 2002 - MAR 2003

· Key Responsibilities:

- · Shift operation management.
- · Customer complaints analysis and reporting.
- · Raise quality awareness in the production lines.
- · Leading production line investigations through RISE process.
- · Process Capability studies

· Achievements:

· Reduction of customer complaints through excellent shift Management and team involvement

DEVELOPMENT ANALYST, PRODUCT AND PROCESS | SMITHKLINE BEECHAMS | SEP 2001 - OCT 2002

· Key Responsibilities:

- · Production Batch records creation, issuance, review and management.
- · Validation of site equipment and facilities.
- · Packaging and raw materials inspection and release.
- · Facility temperature and humidity monitoring.
- · Training.

· Achievements:

· Developed system for identification of defects in materials during inspection.

PROCESS TECHNICIAN | SMITHKLINE BEECHAMS | JUN 1998 - AUG 2001

- · Key Responsibilities:
 - · Manufacturing of Nutritionals Energy drinks and Health drinks.
 - · Participation in product improvement initiatives
 - · Promotion of GMP and overall product, process and human Safety

PERSONAL DETAILS

• **Date of Birth:** 20th march 1973

• Interests: Reading and Computer Software Applications.

• **Membership:** Member of Nairobi University Chemical Club (1995 – 1997).

Leader of the Young Christian Students (1990 - 1991)

REFEREES

Paul Arunga,

Site Director Africa Supply Chain Team Nairobi, Likoni Road

e-mail: Paul.h.arunga@gsk.com
Mobile +254728748160

Jim Hansen

Network Change Lead, GMS EHS/Engineering GlaxoSmithKline, LTD 980 Great West Road, Brentford, Middlesex, TW8 9GS, United Kingdom

e-mail: jim.p.hansen@gsk.com Mobile +07788438592

Manish Sehgal

CH SC AMA Gross Margin Improvement Lead

GlaxoSmithKline, Ltd.

e-mail: manish.2.sehgal@gsk.com

Gateway West, Singapore Mobile: +6596268495